Sam Bindloss

Email: Sam.bindloss@hotmail.com

Phone: 07469204884

Address: 9a Mauldeth Road, Manchester, M20 4NE

Website: www.sambindloss.com

Personal Summary

I consider myself to be an enthusiastic, ambitious and professional individual who sets targets high and will consistently work towards any goal to the best of my ability. I am currently in my third year at Manchester Metropolitan University studying website development and along the way have been involved in managing digital projects, user experience design and building successful websites for clients. In addition to this, I regard myself as having excellent communication and interpersonal skills which I have developed throughout my 4 years of experience in designer boutiques such as Fred Perry, Vilebrequin and French Connection.

Key Attributes

- Professional Work towards success and produce the highest standard of work possible through my time at university and previous work experience.
- Interpersonal skills Perfected this after 4 years of experience in retail.
- Positive attitude Upbeat mind-set and have the energy to get things done.
- Organisational skills Developed through academic studies.
- **Programming languages** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON.
- Computer literate Effective use of Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel.
- Passionate about IT and enjoy all things tech related.
- Willingness to learn and improve as an individual.

Education

Manchester Metropolitan University (2015-2018)

Currently studying towards a degree in (BSc) Website Development. (Expected: 1st)

Blessed George Napier 6th form and Secondary school (2008-2014)

Triple Distinction Star (D*D*D*) in ICT BTEC Extended Diploma.

11 GCSEs from grades A – C including Maths, Science and English.

Regularly attend meetups such as MCR FRED and Deliver Conference to not only gain an increased level of knowledge within my field of work but to also meet and speak to professionals who already work within the digital industry.

Work experience

Prologue Publications – Front-end developer (Internship) (Feb 2018 – Present)

- Front-end developer for a new start-up company looking to release a website for the publications of children's books within the next few months.
- Willingness to work on a project on top of my university work during last year of study.
- Entirely responsible in delivering the landing page and subpages of the website.
- Work closely with client to make sure all his needs are met.

Vilebrequin – Sales assistant (Jun 2017 – Sep 2017)

- Worked well with the team to achieve high sales targets daily.
- Strong interpersonal skills helped drive larger sales.
- Formed lasting relationships with customers.
- Motivated to constantly beat previous sales targets.

Fred Perry - Sales assistant (Jun 2013 - Aug 2016)

- Responsible with supervising members of staff to keep the store running and achieve sales targets.
- Entrusted in opening and closing the store on busy days.
- Ability to delegate fellow employees to reach set tasks.
- Hardworking, honest and loyal member of the team.
- Consistent and strong customer service at all times.

French Connection - Sales assistant (Jun 2012 - Jan 2013)

- Started to become increasingly mature and confident as a person.
- Basic fundamentals learned such as time keeping and presentation.
- Quick in helping customers find what they are looking for and knowledgeable on stock to help drive large sales.
- Experience within the stock room.

References

Johanna Burgess

Vilebrequin store manager – Phone: 073994 24441

Stephen Mclinden

Fred Perry store manager – Phone: 07511 029124